<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<article title="Frequently Asked Questions" short="FAQ">

<!-- ----+---------+---------+---------+---------+---------+---------+----- -->
<content>

<p>
A collection of frequently asked questions that people have frequently asked me
about SconeServer.
</p>

<h2>General</h2>

<h3>Why is it called SconeServer?</h3>
<p>
No particular reason, other than I like scones, and it seems to be a name
that's not being used by any other company or product. 
</p>

<h3>What's wrong with Apache, IIS, etc...?</h3>
<p>
Nothing (as far as I know) - in fact I don't really know very much about Apache
or any other web server for that matter.
I wrote SconeServer for my own amusement, and not to try and improve on any
existing server software. Having said that, I have tried to make SconeServer
as efficient as I possibly can whilst maintaining a good overall structure
to the code, so I hope it would perform reasonably well in comparison to
other similar products.
</p>

<h3>Why should I use it?</h3>
<p>
You shouldn't - unless you want to. It's certainly not a good idea to rely on
an alpha version working perfectly, as there will inevitably be some problems.
</p>

<h2>Installation</h2>

<h3>What platforms will it run on?</h3>
<p>
SconeServer should run on any POSIX compliant system, i.e. UNIX and UNIX-like
systems such as Linux, Open/Free/NetBSD, Darwin and Solaris. It should also run 
on Microsoft Windows. I mainly develop on Slackware Linux, and test on other 
systems periodically, so there is a chance that some problems will creep in 
between tests.
</p>

<h3>How do I install it?</h3>
<p>
Read the <a href="install.html">Installation</a> section.
</p>

<h3>What do I do if it doesn't compile?</h3>
<p>
Don't know.
</p>

<h3>How do I make it run automatically when the machine boots?</h3>
<p>
On UNIX-like systems, this usually involves tinkering about in /etc/rc.d, 
though it is probably best to consult your system's documentation beforehand.
</p>

</content>
<!-- ----+---------+---------+---------+---------+---------+---------+----- -->

</article>
