<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<article short="testbuilder" title="testbuilder - Test Builder System">

<description>
An automated system for downloading, building, and running automated test 
suites on software source distributions. Including a web interface.
<description>

<!-- ----+---------+---------+---------+---------+---------+---------+----- -->
<content>

<p>
The TestBuilder module implements a fully-functional automated system for
downloading, building, and running automated test suites on software source
distributions. It has a web based interface, utilising SconeServer's http
module, as well as a standard SconeScript interface.
</p>

<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>
This is a quick guide to using TestBuilder via the web interface.
</p>

<h3>Profiles</h3>
<p>
Before you start a test build, you must first define a profile. A profile
specifies exactly what steps you want to be performed by the test build. 
Profiles can be saved and reused, so you can start another test sometime in 
the future with exactly the same settings, and you can list all the test builds
that have been performed with a particular profile. You may find there are
already some profiles defined. These are listed under the "Profiles" heading 
on the left of the page.
</p>

<p>
To create a new profile, enter a suitable name in the box on the left (under 
the "Profiles" heading), and click the "New" button. The profile should 
appear in the list on the left, and the profile configuration should be 
displayed. Note: the name of the profile may contain only letters, numbers
and underscores, and must start with a letter.
</p>

<p>
The configuration options for profiles are as follows:
</p>

<h4>Source method and Source location</h4>
<p>
These options define how the system should obtain the source to test. 
Currently there are three options:
</p>
<ul>
<li>
Distribution tarball - In this case the Source location should be a URL from 
which to download the distribution tarball (or zip) file. The URL can be in 
the form "http://..." "ftp://..." "file://..." or simply a local path e.g. 
"/incoming/file.tar.gz" - this is useful if the file is already on the machine.
The file must be a source distribution of the standard type (usually generated
by "make dist"), and can be in gzip (tar.gz), bzip2 (tar.bz2) or zip format.
</li>
<li>
Subversion checkout - In this case the Source location should be the full URL 
of the Subversion repository and branch to checkout. It must be possible to
access the repository anonymously. 
</li>
<li>
CVS checkout -  In this case the Source location should be in the form:
"server path module", for example: "sconeserver.cvs.sourceforge.net /cvsroot/sconeserver sconeserver". Again, it must be possible to login anonymously. 
</li>
</ul>




<h2>SconeScript Interface</h2>

<p>
In addition to the standard module interface, it also has the following:
</p>

  <div class='scr-obj'>
  <h4>
  add ( 
    <span>channel-name : <em>string</em> </span>
  )
  </h4>
  <p>
  Add a new statistics channel.
  </p>
  </div>

  <div class='scr-obj'>
  <h4>
  remove ( 
    <span>channel-name : <em>string</em> </span>
  )
  </h4>
  <p>
  Remove a statistics channel.
  </p>
  </div>

  <div class='scr-obj'>
  <h4>
  list : <em>string</em>
  </h4>
  <p>
  Lists all statistics channels.
  </p>
  </div>

  <div class='scr-obj'>
  <h4>
  &lt;channel-name&gt; : <em>object</em>
  </h4>
  <p>
  Lookup statistics channel given by &lt;channel-name&gt;.
  </p>
  </div>

<h3>Statistics Channels</h3>

  <div class='scr-obj'>
  <h4>
  connections : <em>int</em>
  </h4>
  <p>
  Number of connections recorded by this channel.
  </p>
  </div>

  <div class='scr-obj'>
  <h4>
  input : <em>int</em>
  </h4>
  <p>
  Number of input bytes recorded by this channel.
  </p>
  </div>

  <div class='scr-obj'>
  <h4>
  output : <em>int</em>
  </h4>
  <p>
  Number of output bytes recorded by this channel.
  </p>
  </div>

  <div class='scr-obj'>
  <h4>
  reset ( )
  </h4>
  <p>
  Resets the channel's counters to zero.
  </p>
  </div>


</content>
<!-- ----+---------+---------+---------+---------+---------+---------+----- -->

</article>
